Guide to the Frank J. Novak Photographs of printers' marks, 1460-1599
Department of Special Collections
Novak, Frank J., collector. Photographs of printers' marks,
1460-1599
M1005
Novak, Frank J., collector.
84 prints (1.5 linear ft.)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection contains photographs and photocopies of the printer's marks of various famous European printers.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frank J. Novak, 1997.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Collection contains photographs and photocopies of the printer's marks of various famous European printers.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Book industries and trade--Heraldry.; Devices (Heraldry); Printers' marks.; Printers' ornaments.; Printing.
Collection Contents
- A typewritten list of printer's marks taken from Paul Heitz's multivolume catalog "Die Buchermarken oder Buchdrucker und Verlegerzeichen", Strassburg, Volume 2 as used to identify the card-mounted enlarged photographs in the collection.1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Xerox copies of selected pages from "Printer's and Publisher's Devices in England & Scotland" by Ronald B. Mckerrow, London 1913;& "Bibliographie des Editions de Simon de Colines 1520-1546," par Ph. Renouard, Nieuwkoop, 1962; "Catalogue D'Une Collection Unique de Volumes imprime Les Elzevier",Redige Par Edouard Rahir Nieuwkoop, 1965;"Robert Estienne Royal Printer", by Elizabeth Armstrong, Cambridge Univ. Press, 1954; "A History of the Cambridge University Press", 1521-1921, by S.C. Roberts, M.A. Cambridge Univ. Press, 1921 "Jakob Kobel Zu Oppenheim,1494-1533;Von Josef Benzing, Wiesbaden 1962; "Christopher Plantin", by Colin Clair, Cassell & Co. Ltd. London, ND (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A Xerox copy of selected pages from "Basler Buchermarken" by Paul Heitz, Strassburg, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Xerox copies of "Frankfurter und Mainzer Drucker und Lerlegerzeichen " ,by Paul Heitz, vol. 4.1896. "Spanische und Portugiesische Bucherzeichen' By Konrad Haebler, Strassburg, 1898; "Kolner Buchermarken", by Paul Heitz, Strassburg, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Xerox copies of the "Genfer Buchdrucker und Verlegerzeichen" par Paul Heitz ;Vol. 7, Strassburgh, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Printer; John Siberich - De Octo Partium Orationis Constructione Libellus by Lily & Erasmus Printer: Robert Estienne -Mark used by Estienne as the "King's Printer in Greek" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Printer Jakob Kobel zu Oppenheim [1494-1533]-Astrolabii Declaratio Eiusdemque Usus...Parisiis apud G. Richardum; 1545 Octavo 32 Bl. Sign;A-D8 Paris.-Bib. Nat'l. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Printer; Christopher Plantin {this mark is the combined marks of Christopher Plantin, Jan Steels, &. Philip Nuyts as Joint Publ. Decretales Gregorii 1x [1573] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Christopher Plantin by Colin Clair; Mark of the Vine used by Plantin until 1557 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Printer; Jean Crespin; De Aeterna Dei Praedestinatione-1552 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Printer; Die Familie Estienne [Stephanus]-La Bible[Robert Estienne-1553] Jon Calvin, Commentarius in Librum Psalmorum- 1557 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Printer; Louis Cruse (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Printer ;Jacques Vivian 1513- Heitz Vol. 7 page 49 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Printer; Wygand, Koln 1521-Heita vol. 7 page 37 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Printer; William Caxton; Guido de Monte Rocherii, Manipulis Curatorum -1502[April 22] W. de Worde A second photo duplicating the above from Printer's &.Publisher's Devices by Ronald McKerrow, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Printer; Julian Notary; Statutes 7 Henry V11 etc. [End of 12 & 19 Henry V11-Printer's & Publisher's Devices, Ronald Mckerrow, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Printer; Petrus Treveris -The Noble Experience of the Vertuous Handy Work of Surgery; Braunschweig, H. -Southwark 1525 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Printer; Richard Grafton-Primer, R. Grafton-Printer's &.Publisher's Devicesj, Ronald Mckerrow 1913 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Printer; John Day-Fox J. Acts and Monuments 1563-Mckerrow (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Printer; Simon de Colines, Paris--- Alcabitii Ad Magisterium Judiciorum Astrorum Isagoge Commentario Ionnis Saxonii Declarata - Bibliographie de Colines 1520-1546 Ph. Renouard 1962 pg.13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Printer; Simon de Colines; Divi Severini Boetii Arithmetica Duobus Discreta Libris' Adiecto Commentario. Mysticum Numentorum Applicationem Peristringento--- Bibliographis de Colines, Ph. Renouard 1962, pg. 15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Printer; Friedrich Biel von Basel; --Aesopus Fabulae, Burgos 1496 Heitz vol. 5 pg. 2 Tafe 111 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Printer; Andreas de Bonetis de Papia--- Augustinus Opuscula Heitz vol,2 pg.76 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Printer; Johann Froben-Ludus Annei Senecae de Morte Claudii Caesaris, 1517, Heitz Vol. 3, pg, 24 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Printer; Laurentius Lorius de Portesio - Jo. Candidus Comm. Aquileiens; 1521, Heitz Vol.2 pg. 94 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Printer; Philippus Foyot, No. 69 Senkblei mit devise: Quid inde. Heitz Vol. 2 pg. 22 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Printer; Aldus Manutius Romanus No. 175/2; Heitz Vol. 2 pg.66 See. Uber das Beruhmte Signet des Aldes; Siehe "Renouard. Annales de L'Impr. Des Aldes 3rd Ed. 1834 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Niccolo e Domenico Fratelli dal Jesu No.236/3 Y HS Book-- -- Printer; LR ?Unbekannter Drucker in Florenz X#63 Fioretti de S. Francesco; 1489 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Printer; Baptista de Tortis; No, 323/5 B.T. -Baptista de Tortis und Teil einer Titelumrahmung mit dem Signet; Heitz Vol.2 pg. 126 Book ------- (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Printer; Peter Schaffer Book; Rerum Musicarum Opusculum 1535saa[Argentorat; Apud Petrum Schaffer & Mathiam Apiarum (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Printer; Amand Farkall Book; Novum Testamentum Erasm. Roterdam, 1523 Heitz Vol.1, pg. 148 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Printer; Wolfgang Kopfel Book; Capito, Enarrationes in Habakuk.S. vgl.15 1526 Heitz Vol. 1 pg. 36 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Printer; Plato de Benedictis, Bononiensis Book; No.5 Pla-Plato: die segendeHand Spielt auf den Familiennamen de Benedictus An. 1493 Heitz Vol.2pg.2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Printer; Matthis Biener [Apiarius] Book; Oecolampadius Commentarius in Prophetum Ezechielem T 1534; Heitz Vol.1 Pg. 48 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Printer; Jakob und Johann Cromberger Book; San Gregorio Morales .Sevilla 1527 ;Heitz Vol.5,Pg.7 Tafel7e (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Printer Crafft Muller [Crato Mylius] Book; Paraleipomena Rerum Memorabilium Historiae Abbatis Urspergensis Annexas 5 1539 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Printer; Bernhard Richel Book; Decretum Gratiani cum Glossis Bartomei Briziensis 1476-Heitz Vol. 3 Pg. 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Printer; Jacob von Pfortzen Book Grammatica, Francis Nigri 1499-Heitz Vol.3. Pg.6 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Printer; Johann Froben auch Hieronymus Froben Book; Gregorius. De Theologia Libri 1523 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Printer; Froben Book; Dieses Zeichen befindertsich auf 1.Bron B.V. von einer rohen ein fassen umgeben (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Printer; Adam Petri, Heirich Petri, und Sebastian Henricpetri Book; Sedulius Collectaneum in Epist. Pauli T. 1528 Heitz Vol. 3 Pg.52 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Printer; Michael Isengrin Book; Euacandiratio Tribus in Libris Luculenter Perstricta, Ioanne Petro Merenda a Brixiano; Heitz Vol3 Pg. 86 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Printer Johannes Antonius de Benedictus Book; Platina De Honesta Voluptate 1499 Heitz Vol.2 Pg. 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Printer; Nicolaus de Gorgonzola Book; Ovid; Metamorphoses 1509 Heitz Vol 2. Pg. 22 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Printer; Johannes Jacobus de Benedictis Bononiensis Book; Macarius Mutius Camers Divi Sebastiani Encomion 1523 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Printer; Lucas Antonius Giunta Florentiuus Book; Tabulae Alphonsinae Heitz Vol2. Pg. 82 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Printer; Thomas Anshelm Book; Melancthon Grammatica Graeca s. 1520 Heitz Vol.1 pg. 126 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Printer; Leonardus de GerulaBook; 1494 in: Anton de Butrio. Rep. De Nov. et Vet. De Cohab. Heitz Vol.2 pg. 46 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Printer; Robert Estienne, Parisien, Imprimeur du Roy; Olive tree used by Estienne 1526-8 Book; M. T. Ciceronis Opera{1539} &. Eusebius, "Evangelica Demonstratio {1545-6} (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Printer; Johannes Petrus de Bonominis de Cremona Book; Perottus, Rudimenta Grammaticae {1486} Heitz Vol.2. pg. 14 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Printer; Compagnia del Drago {Societas Colubris} Book; Riceptario di doctori {1498} Heitz Vol.2.pg. 14 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Printer; Melchior Sessa {katze mit maus} Book; Albumasar, Introductor, In Astronom. {1506} Sessa was also Marco Polo's publisher. Heitz Vol.2 pg. 116 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Printer; Benedetto Fontana Book; 1495 in. Horatius: 1497 in Diogenes Laertius: Vitae Philosophorum Heitz Vol.2 pg. 80 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Printer; Johann Fust und Peter Schoeffer Book; Bibla Latina Vulgata 1462 Heitz Vol. 4 Tafel 1. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Printer; Johann Schott Book; 1501. Baptista Mantuanus. Parthenicae S' Heitz Vol 1. Pg. 4 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Printer; Johann Amerbach mit Petri von Langendorf und Johann Froben Book; Decretum Gratiani Heitz Vol 3. Pg. 2 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Printer; Johannes Baptista Phaellus Book; Galenus. Libri Anatomici 1529 Heitz Vol 2. Pg. 6 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Printer; Konrad Winters von Homborch Book 1476; Historia Longobardica Heitz Vol. 6 pg. Tafel 3 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Printer Antonius Zarotus Parmensis Book Leonard Aretinus. L'Aquila Volants 1495 Heitz Vol. 2 pg. 38 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Printer; Jean Crespin Book Commentarii in Epistolas Canonicas 1554 {Calvin} Heitz Vol 7 pg; 17 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Printer; Di Familie Chovet Book; -----Heitz Vol 7. Pg. 13 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Printer; William Caxton Book; Missal ad usum Sarum {this figure from Lord Newton's copy 1487 Paris Printers and Publisher's Devices by Ronald McKerrow 1913 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Printer; Peter Schott Book; Lucubraciunculae Ornatissimae 1498 Heitz Vol 1, pg. 4 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Printer; Heinrich von Nuss Book; Borseverein, Loses Blatt Heitz; vol.6 Tafel 8 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Printer; Hermann Bungart von Kettwig Book; Unterweisung wie ein christlicher Mann Sterben Soll Heitz vol.6 Tafel 4-16 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Printer; Francisco und Luis Sanchez Book ;Antonio Fuenmayor, Vida Hechos de Pio V Ponticie Romano. Madrid 1593 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Printer; Johann Rosenbach Book; Constitutions Fetes Per D. Ferrando, Barcelona 1494 Heitz; vol. 5 page 2 Tafel XI (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Printer; Juan Lopez Perete Book; Juan Arias, Practica Ecclesiastica Madrid, 1585 Heitz Vol 5 page 35 Tafel XXXV (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Printer;Johann Rosenbach Book Francesh Eximenes. Libre dels Angels Barcelona 1494 Heitz vol.5 page 10 TafelX (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Printer Johann Rosenbach Book; Francesch Eximenes- De Les Dones, Barcelona, 1495 Heitz vol. 5 page 10 Tafel X (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Printer; Paul Hurus Book; Andres de Li Repetorio de los Tiempos Saragossa 1495 Heitz vol. 1 page 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Printer; Peter Michael und Diego Gumiel Book; Ramon Lull, Ars Inventiva Veritatatis Valencia 1515 Heitz vol5 page 9 Tafel IX (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Printer; Peter Schoeffer Book; In Hortulus Animae 1512 Heitz Vol 4 Tafel 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Printer; Andreas Wechel und seine Nachfolger Book Apud Claudium Marnium, et Haeredesl; Joan Aubrii 1607 Heitz vol 4 Tafel LX11 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Printer; Baptista de Pederzani Brizanus Book; DellaNuova Hispagna 1524; Ferdinando Cortese Heitz vol. 2 page 98 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Printer; Georgius de Ruscavibus Mediolanensis Book; Ovid Heitz vol 2 page 106 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Printer; Petrus Liectenstein Coloniensis Book; Ptolemaeus Almagestum 1503 Heitz vol2 page 32 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Printer; Johannes Oswalt civis Augustensis Book; Breviarum S. ecdes Salzburgens Heitz vol.2 page 96 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Printer; Aldus Manutius Romanus Book; Ueber des Beruhmtes Signet des Aldus siehe Rnouard. Annales de L'Impr. Des Aldes III Ed 1834 Heitz vol.2 page 66 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Printer; Niccolo de Domenico Fratelli dal Jesu Book; Chiromantia-Andreas Corvus Heitz vol. 2 page 88 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Printer; Officina de Leyde-Jean Elzevier Book; Het Nieuwe Testaments Les Elzevier & Divers Typographie Hollandais du XVII Siecle (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Printer; Officine des Blaeu D'Amsterdam Book; Memoires de Messire Pierre de Bourdeile, Seigneur de Brantome Les Elzeviers & Divers Typographie Hollandais du XVII Siecle (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Printer; Andreas de Torresanis de Asula Book; Duns Scotus. Sup. Sententiarr Heitz; vol. 2 page 124 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Printer; Officine de Leyde de Bonaventure und Abraham Elzevier Book; Scoti, Poemata quae Extant Lugo. Bat. 1628 Les Elzeviers & Divers Typographes Hollandais de XVII siecle (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Printer; Bernardinus de Garaldis Book; Rochus de Curte; Fert. Consuetud. Tractatus Heitz vol. 2 page 46 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Printer; Simon de Colines Book; Elegantiarum Libri Sex., Denvo Recogniti cum siusdem de Reciprocis Pronominibus Libello/; Paris 1527 Bibliographie de Colines, Ph. Renouard 1962 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Printer; Andreas de Bonetis de Papia Book Augustinus Opuscula 1484 Heitz vol. 2 page 76 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Printer; Dionysius Bertochus Bononiensis Book; Scriptores rei rusticae Heitz vol. 2 page 70 (Box 3, Folder 13)